[Music]
my name is paola
it's a popular name in my mother's
native country of puerto rico
it means small which is ironic since
thanks to my american father i'm five
feet
and nine inches i've always been
interested
in country living my need for quietness
drew me to my home
in northeast washington also my wish to
help preserve
this beautiful place here in my valley
spring is nation
the soil is finally workable and it is
rich
long mist after four months buried under
[Music]
snow
i don't know of a single definition of
living simply that applies to everyone
i believe you can live mindfully and
sustainably most anywhere
depending on what's reasonable for you
for example
i try to avoid over consumption but i've
never been
a minimalist in the more mainstream
sense of the turn when i've tried it i
have failed
miserably i like to have many things in
my life and value what they can do for
me
i have about a thousand hobbies and each
comes with a set of craft supplies
when all of it is laid out you would be
shocked at the amount of books and paint
and paper and ribbon
that i own
[Music]
i indulge my love of crafting and design
and purchase as needed
what has changed is the amount of
thought i put into bringing something
new into my home
and where and how it is made
[Music]
as you can see my home is only one room
and mostly floor space
i've put a lot of thought into what i
bring into it most of the items are
between 2 and thirty dollars
and that is including my new table which
was bought at auction for cheap
since one of the legs had fallen off
nothing that a new screw can't fix
as i was making this video i realized
that i've slowly adopted my true form as
a squirrel
and have a growing collection of little
objects
my boyfriend is also a collector of
pretty things and so the realization is
a bit concerning
since together we could probably start
our own museum in another decade
[Music]
what i do appreciate about each item in
my home is that the vast majority of it
is old they have been found while
perusing antique shops and thrift stores
some items are over 100 years old others
are recently secondhand
the new items are mostly gifts i can't
avoid
buying new things as needed but once i
started prioritizing second hand and
reusing items
many things became far more affordable
for example i painted most of my walls
instead of using wallpaper
sprayed old furniture to look new
thrifted and eclectic but hopefully
charming set of dishware
the same goes for my clothes which i try
to source locally
though it can be tricky for someone of
my height depending on what i'm looking
for
so i do my best to avoid synthetic
fabric if i'm purchasing
something new
[Music]
i'm an artist after all and can
confidently say that things of beauty
though maybe not practical
do add value to my daily life be it a
work of art or a beautifully made piece
of furniture
a teacup many of these items are well
crafted and will last a lifetime
and it feels like owning a piece of
history while i'm not emotionally
dependent on these things
they bring me joy to use and look at
every day
the reason i'm highlighting all these
random things in my cottage cottages
because
while reflecting on the future of us as
humans
i consider the fact that while we can
never stop consuming
we can consume differently and that's i
think our greatest hope
i love interior design and i think there
shouldn't be any reason i need to give
up what i love
i simply look for new ways to sustain my
hobbies that bring the planet into
consideration
i will definitely give you a more
thorough spring tour of the cottage once
the garden is up and running
take care and i will see you next week
sending my love
[Music]
ugh
you